Finding Aid for the Lawrence Clark Powell Papers LSC.0229
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Manuscripts Of Articles And Lectures, ca. 1950-1971
  - Boxes 83-104
    - Home - Jn
      - Islandia. English 4G, Los Angeles County Branch Librarians, January 11, 1956. February 8, 1956. (Box 91, Folder 14)
      - It's Always Fair Weather. Los Angeles Bookfair, 1967. (Box 91, Folder 15)
      - Jackson, W.A. Records of a Bibliographer. LCP review, August 67. (Box 91, Folder 16)
      - Jacob Blanck -- Introduction to Lecture on Children's Literature. Simmons Coll. Grolier, April 27, 1954. (Box 91, Folder 17)
      - Robinson Jeffers. (Box 91, Folder 18)
      - Robinson Jeffers -- English 4F (Narrative Poetry), May 25, 1949; February 23, 1955. (Box 91, Folder 19)
      - Robinson Jeffers Recognition Program. Occidental College, November 8, 1962. (Box 91, Folder 20)
      - Jeffers Review. (Box 91, Folder 21)
      - Jeffers Letters, 1968. (Box 91, Folder 22)
      - Jefferson, Thomas. Notes for possible talk, February 1956. (Box 91, Folder 23)
      - Jewish Libraries; Friends of the Jewish Community Library, January 16, 1956. (Box 91, Folder 24)
    - Jo - Librarian
      - Jordan-Smith, Paul. Review by LCP--Caxton Printers. (Folder 1)
      - Jordan-Smith, Paul. Memorial, 21 June 1971. (Box 92, Folder 2)
      - Joys and Sorrows of University Librarianship -- UC School of Librarianship, January 20, 1953. (Box 92, Folder 3)
      - Junior League of Los Angeles, April 30, 1971. (Box 92, Folder 4)
      - Know Your Library. Foreword, 1955-1956. (Box 92, Folder 5)
      - Laguna Beach High School Library Dedication, May 21, 1955. (Box 92, Folder 6)
      - Land of Fiction (Bibliography of California) -- Also given for Severance Club, 1952. September, 1953. (Box 92, Folder 7)
      - Landscapes and Bookscrapes. Friends of Bancroft Library, May 4, 1958. (Box 92, Folder 8)
      - The Landscape & Literature. John F. Kennedy Memorial Library, California State College at Los Angeles (National Library Week), April 15, 1964. (Box 92, Folder 9)
      - Landscape with Books. In Southwest Review, Summer 1959. (Box 92, Folder 10)
      - Landscape with Books. 8th American Southwest Writers' Conference & Workshop, June 23, 1958. (Box 92, Folder 11)
      - Language of the Heart. Printed by Los Angeles City College, as keepsake., Fall of 1957 (Box 92, Folder 12)
      - Language of the Heart. Los Angeles City College, February 20, 1957. (Box 92, Folder 13)
      - Lawrence, D.H., by Irwin Swerdlow., Ward Ritchie Press., February 1965 (Box 92, Folder 14)
        A Critique of manuscript by LCP.
      - Lawrence Book--never written, 1934. (Box 92, Folder 15)
      - Leadbrand Guide--LCP--Foreword, 1966. (Box 92, Folder 16)
      - Learning to Teach, Teaching to Learn. In California Librarian, October 1954. (Box 92, Folder 17)
      - Lewis, W. One Man's Education. Review for New York Times Book Review, July 1967. (Box 92, Folder 18)
      - Librarian and Writer. Tennessee Library Association, May 6, 1966. (Box 92, Folder 19)
      - Librarian and Writer. OLA, April 22, 1966. (Box 92, Folder 20)
      - Librarian and Writer. Illinois Library Association, October 28, 1965. (Box 92, Folder 21)
      - Librarian in California History. Extension Division. Dawson's Bookshop, November 13, 1956. (Box 92, Folder 22)
      - Librarian in Orbit. (Box 92, Folder 23)
        Spoken on several occasions--see blue card.
      - Librarian on Leave. ABA, October 1950. (Box 92, Folder 24)
      - Librarian on Leave -- Journal of National Book League, January 1951. (Box 92, Folder 25)
    - Librarians - Lit
      - Librarians and their Books. In Saturday Review, April 11, 1959. (Box 93, Folder 1)
      - Librarians as Readers of Books. PNLA. Seattle, September 1947. (Box 93, Folder 2)
      - Librarianship in California -- CLA Centennial Conference. Sacremento, June 24, 1950. (Box 93, Folder 3)
      - Libraries and Learning (Occassional Paper no.5). Bigbliography English 195, Spring 1956, 1957. (Box 93, Folder 4)
      - Library Development Committee Report. CLA, October 23, 1952. (Box 93, Folder 5)
      - The Library in the Expanding University. American Association of University Professors, March 5, 1959. (Box 93, Folder 6)
      - Library Journal, On the Grindstone., 1961-62. (Box 93, Folder 7)
      - Library Journal. Correspondence. (Box 93, Folder 8)
      - Library of Congress Exhibit Opening--Sacremento, June 21, 1950. (Box 93, Folder 9)
      - Library Staff Association Metting. Introduction of Lawrence Lipton, January 17, 1962. (Box 93, Folder 10)
      - Libros Californianos. Jake Zeitlin, publisher. (Box 93, Folder 11)
      - Lilienthal, Ted--Memorial, 1972. (Box 93, Folder 12)
      - Lifegiving Powers of the Public Library. Milwaukee Public Library Festival, November 29, 1956. (Box 93, Folder 13)
      - Literature of Southern California. Authors Club, Hollywood Roosevelt., March 17, 1956. (Box 93, Folder 14)
      - Literature of the Southwest. In The Masterkey, September 1961. (Box 93, Folder 15)
      - Little Package (World, )., 1963 (Box 93, Folder 16)
      - Little Package. Commencement Address, University of Arizona, May 31, 1961. (Box 93, Folder 17)
      - Little Sermon on Binding. The Rub-Off issue., January-February 1958 (Box 93, Folder 18)
      - Little Package. Published by Arizona Librarian, Southwest Review, America's Leaders Speak to Youth. (Box 93, Folder 19)
    - Liu - Mam
      - Living Hand to Book. Powellogue...Scripps Convocation,, Zamorano,, Faculty Women's Club, January 14, 1958 January 8, 1958 January 21, 1958. (Box 94, Folder 1)
      - Living with Books. Institute for Teachers Inyo County, Lone Pine, March 4, 1955. (Box 94, Folder 2)
      - Lodge-Engelbarts Dinner, June 16, 1967. (Box 94, Folder 3)
      - Long Beach Local Literature. Rancho Los Cerritos, October 2, 1956. (Box 94, Folder 4)
      - Los Angeles Public Library, November 19, 1958. (Box 94, Folder 5)
      - Los Angeles, A Reader's Guide to. Sunset-lane, Spring 1967. (Box 94, Folder 6)
      - Los Angeles Public Library--oral exam, May 1970. (Box 94, Folder 7)
      - Loughborough. (Box 94, Folder 8)
      - Loughborough, School of Librarianship (College of Further Education) talk to students, Spring 1963. (Box 94, Folder 9)
      - Lummis, Charles. Albuquerque. Southwest Library Association, November 3, 1954. (Box 94, Folder 10)
      - Lummis, by Dudley Gordon. LCP Foreword, April 1972. (Box 94, Folder 11)
      - Lure of Californiana. Berkeley/Davis campuses, June 1964. (Box 94, Folder 12)
      - Lycoming College, dedication and degree, May 1968. (Box 94, Folder 13)
      - Mackenzie, Armine D. California Librarian (review by LCP of a fine contagion). (Box 94, Folder 14)
      - Magee foreword, 1973. (Box 94, Folder 15)
      - Magnetic Field of Books. University of Tennessee,; Emory University Georgia,; University New Mexico,; Valley University Women, March 5, 1954 April 2, 1954 June 29, 1954 February 15, 1955. (Box 94, Folder 16)
      - Magnetic Field of Books (Correspondence). (Box 94, Folder 17)
      - Making of a Poet. Robinson Jeffers Celebration. Occidental College, June 10, 1955. (Box 94, Folder 18)
      - Making of a Poet. In Southwest Review. (Box 94, Folder 19)
      - Malibu Manna. In Hoja Volante, February 1956. (Box 94, Folder 20)
      - Malibu Book, edition., 1970 (Box 94, Folder 21)
      - Malibu Park Junior High School. Address to students about European trip (1963), February 7, 1964. (Box 94, Folder 22)
    - Man - Neu
      - Man looks to his own creative powers. Speech--Pasadena City College Forum, November 12, 1963. (Box 95, Folder 1)
      - Manhattan Winter -- Hoja Volante,; California Librarian, February 1952 March 1952. (Box 95, Folder 2)
      - Man Named Dobie -- Keepsake for Glen Dawson, 1954. (Box 95, Folder 3)
      - Marlborough School Talk, February 10, 1960. (Box 95, Folder 4)
      - Mean What You Say. 2nd Annual UCLA Library Conference. Goleta, July 20-23, 1958. (Box 95, Folder 5)
      - Medical Librarians of Southern California. LCP address to Student Union, October 1961. (Box 95, Folder 6)
      - Memoirs of Sydney Mitchell. Menno Hertzberger, 1960. (Box 95, Folder 7)
      - Mercurius Redivivus. Clark Library Publication. (Box 95, Folder 8)
      - Mid-century authors. H.W. Wilson Company. (Box 95, Folder 9)
      - Miller, Henry --the last..., Corle Book Contest. Santa Barbara, April 26, 1965. (Box 95, Folder 10)
      - Mitchell of California -- ALA Midwinter. Chicago, 1954. (Box 95, Folder 11)
        Also, memoirs, 1960.
      - Mitchell, S.B. (LCP's citation, org. )., ca. 1946. (Box 95, Folder 12)
      - Monterey Park Talk, (no title, off the cuff)., 1960 (Box 95, Folder 13)
      - Moore, E.C. Los Angeles Times, February 7, 1955. (Box 95, Folder 14)
      - Moore, E.C. Memorial Address, February 15, 1955. (Box 95, Folder 15)
      - More Gold in you Attic. Review by LCP for Los Angeles Times, January 1962. (Box 95, Folder 16)
      - More Precious Than Oil. Long Beach P.L., B.L. Smith, Sr. Lecture, April 10, 1959. (Box 95, Folder 17)
      - Mozart's Blood Brother - speech to Zamorano Club dinner meeting, November 4, 1964. (Box 95, Folder 18)
      - Mr. Southwest. Texas Western Press, September 1, 1963. (Box 95, Folder 19)
      - Mr. Southwest: J. Frank Dobie of Texas. In Arizona Highways, January 1957. (Box 95, Folder 20)
      - Multum in Parvo -- Dedication of La Verne College Library, September 16, 1951. (Box 95, Folder 21)
      - The Music in My Life. Pasadena Browning Society, 1954; Severance Club, September 1954. (Box 95, Folder 22)
      - Music into Silence -- Pacific-Spectator,; Santa Barbara Home Life, Winter 1951 December 1951 and January 1952. (Box 95, Folder 23)
      - Musical Blood Brothers. Keepsake for Zamorano/Roxburge meeting, Published by LCP., September 66. (Box 95, Folder 24)
      - Musical Blood Brothers. USC; CLA Southern District; Library Patrons, Occidental, March 10, 1966 April 16, 1966 April 18, 1966. (Box 95, Folder 25)
      - My Biggest Flop. In Antiquarian Bookman,; A Passion for Books--World, 1958 1959. (Box 95, Folder 26)
      - My Favorite Four-Letter Word. In Antiquarian Bookman Yearbook,; California Librarian, 1956 July 1957. (Box 95, Folder 27)
      - Nevada Library Association. Reno, Nevada, October 19-21, 1962. (Box 95, Folder 28)
    - New - New York Times Book Review
      - New Look at Library Administration. Institute for LJ, 1957 December 1957. (Box 96, Folder 1)
      - New Mexico Highlands University -- Guest Lecturer, Summer 1961. (Box 96, Folder 2)
      - New Mexico North. In Southwest Review, Autumn 1956. (Box 96, Folder 3)
      - New Mexico, University Press. (Box 96, Folder 4)
      - New York Times Book Review Speaking of Books, February 1960. (Box 96, Folder 5)
      - New York Times Review, and correspondence., 1961- (Box 96, Folder 6)
      - New York Times. (Box 96, Folder 7)
      - New York Times Review, 1961-. (Box 96, Folder 8)
      - New York Times Book Review (various articles and reviews). (Box 96, Folder 9)
      - New York Times Baggage II. (Box 96, Folder 10)
      - New York Times. California in Connecticut. (Box 96, Folder 11)
      - New York Times: Phillips Review. (Box 96, Folder 12)
      - New York Times Book Review Speaking of Books--L.A., November 12, 1963. (Box 96, Folder 13)
      - New York Times Book Review (re H. Stevens), Speaking of Books., January 1964. (Box 96, Folder 14)
      - New York Times Book Review. Review by LCP of Einginder's Myth of the Britannica, January 1964. (Box 96, Folder 15)
      - Speaking of Books (on Rexroth), October 1964. (Box 96, Folder 16)
      - My Paperback World New York Times Book Review, December 1963. (Box 96, Folder 17)
      - Speaking of Books (New York Times Book Review) On Yeats, October 1964. (Box 96, Folder 18)
      - New York Times Book Review, - Make Mine a Small One., November 1964 (Box 96, Folder 19)
      - New York Times Book Review - Henry Miller, submitted, March 30, 1965. (Box 96, Folder 20)
      - New York Times Book Review, November 11, 1962. (Box 96, Folder 21)
        re Mozart (Speaking of Books).
      - Queen Calafia's Island, by Duffus, R.L. Reviewed by LCP for New York Times Book Review, submitted, August 30, 1965. (Box 96, Folder 22)
    - Nex - On
      - Next to Mother's Milk. Family School Alliance, UES, November 9, 1959. (Box 97, Folder 1)
      - No Life Without Books. Beverly Hills Women's Club,; School Library Association, June 30, 1958; Taft College Faculty, October 21, 1958 February 19, 1959. (Box 97, Folder 2)
      - Nothing Else Matters -- Hoja Volante, April, 1953. (Box 97, Folder 3)
      - Northland Press in the Pinewood. In Arizona Highways, March 1963. (Box 97, Folder 4)
      - Novelists' Southwest. In Los Angeles Times, Monday February 21, 1955. (Box 97, Folder 5)
      - Novels and Novelists of the Great Southwest. Severance Club, September 23, 1955. (Box 97, Folder 6)
      - Oak Grove Summer. In Hoja Volante. (Box 97, Folder 7)
      - Oak Grove Winter. In Hoja Volante. (Box 97, Folder 8)
      - Occasional Papers, foreword to. (Box 97, Folder 9)
      - Oases of Books. In Arizona Highways. (Box 97, Folder 10)
      - Occasional Letters to the Faculty (Correspondence). (Box 97, Folder 11)
      - Occasional Letters to the Faculty (no.1-8, 9). (Box 97, Folder 12)
      - Occidental College Alumni Award, June 1967. (Box 97, Folder 13)
      - Occidental College, address to, October 18, 1961. (Box 97, Folder 14)
      - Occidental College, Library dedication, January 20, 1971. (Box 97, Folder 15)
      - Occupation, Student. In Hoja Volante, October 1956. (Box 97, Folder 16)
      - Ocean in View. In Hoja Volante, Summer 1956. (Box 97, Folder 17)
      - Old Refrain. CLA Sacremento, Fall 1959. (Box 97, Folder 18)
      - Ole Olin. ()., October 1968 (Box 97, Folder 19)
      - On Being Up in the Air. In California Librarian, December 1963. (Box 97, Folder 20)
      - On Conspiring to Inspire. In Wilson Library Bulletin, Library Conference, Goleta., 1958. (Box 97, Folder 21)
        See also Mean What You Say.
      - On Getting and Giving Books, December 1961. (Box 97, Folder 22)
      - On Mozart. Speech, Zamorano Club., November 6, 1963 (Box 97, Folder 23)
      - On Recruiting, Especially Catalogers. CLA Annual Meeting, Occidental, April 17, 1948. (Box 97, Folder 24)
      - On the Road to Salzburg. In Hoja Volante, 1962. (Box 97, Folder 25)
      - On the Virtue of Smallneys. Occidental College. Hoja Volante., April 8, 1952. (Box 97, Folder 26)
    - One - Rea
      - One Book in a Million. Los Angeles County Public Library, May 16, 1956. (Box 98, Folder 1)
      - One Librarian's View of the Southwest. Friends of the Arcadia Public Library, January 12, 1962. (Box 98, Folder 2)
      - Open Letter of Welcome to Raynard C. Swank, Upon his Appointment as Dean of the School of Librarianship at the U. of C. In California Librarian, July, 1969. (Box 98, Folder 3)
      - Our Literary Heritage. USF Workshop, July 16, 1965. (Box 98, Folder 4)
      - Panels and Symposia. UCLA Music Department, 1956. (Box 98, Folder 5)
      - Pasadena City College Library Dedication, October 1949. (Box 98, Folder 6)
      - Passion for Books. (Box 98, Folder 7)
      - Phi Beta Kappa Installation--Riverside Campus, (talk on Miller also)., April 7, 1965 (Box 98, Folder 8)
      - Phi Beta Kappa Alpha Alumni Association Honorary Councilor. (Box 98, Folder 9)
      - Philosopher Pickett. University of California Press-Berkeley, 1942. (Box 98, Folder 10)
      - Picture Taker of the Southwest. In Westways, 1958. (Box 98, Folder 11)
      - Place of Intense Radiation. In New Mexico Quarterly, June 1965. (Box 98, Folder 12)
      - Poetry of Walt Whitman. (Box 98, Folder 13)
      - Poet's Land. Big Sur Guide. (Box 98, Folder 14)
      - Powell, Lawrence Clark, by Neal Harlow. ALA Bulletin, 1953. (Box 98, Folder 15)
      - Power and the Glory. In California Librarian. Pasadena Women's City Club, March 6, 1956. (Box 98, Folder 16)
      - Power of Books. Interfraternity Council Mothers' Club, June 1, 1956. (Box 98, Folder 17)
      - Power to Evoke -- National Society of Autograph Collections. Columbus, Ohio, May 4, 1953. (Box 98, Folder 18)
      - Prime Pickings in Paperbacks. In Herald Examiner, June 1962. (Box 98, Folder 19)
      - Printing for the Library. Foreword by LCP William Holman, May 1965. (Box 98, Folder 20)
      - Problem of Rare Books in the College and University Library -- College & University Librarians, Redlands, November 5, 1938. (Box 98, Folder 21)
      - Prospect Before Us. Book Club of California San Francisco., December 8, 1962. (Box 98, Folder 22)
      - Publishers on Publishing. A Review by LCP Gerald Gross author for CRL. (Box 98, Folder 23)
      - Purple Sage and Western Stars. County Women's Medical Auxiliary, Valley Branch,; Chapel Hill, North Carolina, November 22, 1955 October 28, 1956. (Box 98, Folder 24)
      - R.A. (Richard Adlington) in Los Angeles. To be printed in a booklet of tributes, Southern Illinois University. (Box 98, Folder 25)
      - Randall, Dukedom, Review of, 1969. (Box 98, Folder 26)
      - Rare Book Rooms and Special Collections Dedication, August 1, 1950. (Box 98, Folder 27)
      - Rare Books in the University Library: Policy and Administration -- ACRL. Atlantic City, June 17, 1948. (Box 98, Folder 28)
      - Reader's Adviser. Bowker. Revisions by LCP, November 1967. (Box 98, Folder 29)
      - Reader's Guide to the Southwest. Netherlands (Hertzberger) and University of Oklahoma Press. (Box 98, Folder 30)
      - Reading in Orbit. In Los Angeles Examiner, November 13, 1960. (Box 98, Folder 31)
      - Reading on the Malibu. In California Librarian, August 29, 1955. (Box 98, Folder 32)
    - Rec - San
      - Recollections of an Ex-Bookseller. In Zeitlin Keepsake, 1949. (Box 99, Folder 1)
      - Rendezvous in Cadogan Square. Manuscripts. Manuscript Society Los Angeles, 1958. July 10, 1958. (Box 99, Folder 2)
      - Report from the President -- CLA Southern District Meeting, March 4, 1950. (Box 99, Folder 3)
      - Resources Unlimited: Special Collections at UCLA, 1953. (Box 99, Folder 4)
      - Responsibilities of Southern California in Southwestern Library Development. Southwest Conference Oxy., April 16, 1955. (Box 99, Folder 5)
      - Return of the Native -- Hoja Volante, July, 1954. (Box 99, Folder 6)
      - Return to France -- Pacific Spectator, Summer 1951. (Box 99, Folder 7)
      - Return to the Heartland. Texas Library Association, Houston., April 17, 1959. (Box 99, Folder 8)
      - Return to the Valley. CLA, Yosemite District, annual meeting. Visalia, April 4, 1959. (Box 99, Folder 9)
      - Revista Nueva Mexicana. In Southwest Review 56. New Mexico Magazine, 1958. (Box 99, Folder 10)
      - Rexroth Bibliography, Foreword. (Box 99, Folder 11)
      - Rivers and Reading -- Address at dedication of Beeghly Library, Juniata College, Huntington, Pennsylvania., October 11, 1963. (Box 99, Folder 12)
      - Riverside Talk. 500,000th volume., December 3, 1969. (Box 99, Folder 13)
      - Roasting an Old Chestnut -- ACRL, Midwinter 1954. (Box 99, Folder 14)
      - Roosevelt Rough Riders (foreword) New American Library of World Literature, 1961. (Box 99, Folder 15)
      - Roots of Regional Literature. New Mexico Highlands University, June 29, 1959. (Box 99, Folder 16)
      - Rose Mitchell. California Librarian, January 1956. (Box 99, Folder 17)
      - Rosenbach, A Biography. In New York Times Book Review, October 1960. (Box 99, Folder 18)
      - Roundup of the Waters. In New Mexico Magazine, February 1958; June 1962. (Box 99, Folder 19)
      - Rutgers Talk, April 25, 1968. (Box 99, Folder 20)
      - SLS, Address to graduates (also )., September 1968. 1971 (Box 99, Folder 21)
      - San Antonio Public Library Survey. (Box 99, Folder 22)
      - San Diego Area (untitled), November 1, 1956. (Box 99, Folder 23)
    - Santa - Som
      - Santa Barbara Talk (Santa Barbara Public Library)., June 11, 1962. (Box 100, Folder 1)
      - Sayers Award, January 1970. (Box 100, Folder 2)
      - Sayers, Frances C. Introduction to: CLA, 1964. (Box 100, Folder 3)
      - Sayers, Frances Clark--foreword to a collection of her essays by Marjeanne Blinn. (Box 100, Folder 4)
      - School of Library Service -- Class of, 1964. (Box 100, Folder 5)
      - Sci-Tech News, November 1958. (Box 100, Folder 6)
      - Schursch, Jack. Class of 1930 (1905-1965) Phi Gamma Delta (Oxy), in memoriam., November 1965 (Box 100, Folder 7)
      - Scriabin -- Gerhart Muench Recital, July 15, 1963. (Box 100, Folder 8)
      - Sea, As Seen by El Sea Powell. Published by Dawson's Bookstore. (Box 100, Folder 9)
      - Sense of the Past. Historical Society of Southern California, November 21, 1958. (Box 100, Folder 10)
      - Shake Well & Speak, Allied Arts Association Festival,; Houston Public Library and other occasions., March 10, 1955 (Box 100, Folder 11)
      - Shelf of Books About the Seacoast, Mountains, and Deserts of Southern California -- Ford Times, May 1962. (Box 100, Folder 12)
      - Shoe on Other Foot. (Box 100, Folder 13)
      - Shoestring Press, 1967-. (Box 100, Folder 14)
      - Sky, Sun, & Water -- Southwest Review, 1954. (Box 100, Folder 15)
      - Simmons College, 1966-68. (Box 100, Folder 16)
      - Sky, Sun, & Water (F.W. Hodge) -- Zamorano Club, October 28, 1953. (Box 100, Folder 17)
      - Small Hobby Horse -- Hobby Show, 1953. (Box 100, Folder 18)
      - Some Angelic Reading Matter. (Box 100, Folder 19)
      - Smith, Ralph McKnight. Words spoken in memoriam, March 1965. (Box 100, Folder 20)
      - Some Great California Book Collectors. ABAA, Extension,; School Librarians' Association, Mills College, March 7, 1950 March 11, 1951. (Box 100, Folder 21)
      - Some Novelists of the Southwest. Southwest Museum, February 19, 1956. (Box 100, Folder 22)
      - Some Novels About Los Angeles --Los Angeles Times, November 12, 1953. (Box 100, Folder 23)
      - Some Novels of the Purple Sage. Caxton Club, Chicago, and Houston P.L. panel, February 4, 1955 March 10, 1955. (Box 100, Folder 24)
      - Some Seasonal and Permanent Joys of Reading. Glendale AAUW, December 10, 1955. (Box 100, Folder 25)
      - Something for Everyone. California Library Association, Southern District. UCLA, May 9, 1959. (Box 100, Folder 26)
    - Sou- Ten
      - Source of Power and Beauty -- Dedication of Montana State College Library. Bozeman, May 10, 1950. (Box 101, Folder 1)
      - South from Lisbon. (Box 101, Folder 2)
      - South Pasadena Public Library, March 21, 1950. (Box 101, Folder 3)
      - South of Tehachapi -- Orange County Library Club, Fullerton,; National Association of State Libraries, Los Angeles, April 15, 1953 June 19, 1953. (Box 101, Folder 4)
      - South Pasadena Talk, (California project)., January 20, 1970 (Box 101, Folder 5)
      - Southwest Broadsides. (Box 101, Folder 6)
      - Southwest and Edwin Corle -- Preface to Fig Tree John, July, 1954. (Box 101, Folder 7)
      - Southwest Literature and Libraries. Tucson, October 1971. (Box 101, Folder 8)
      - Southwest: Proving Ground for Librarians. In New Mexico Library Bulletin, July, 1962. (Box 101, Folder 9)
      - Southwestern Century. Non-fiction bibliography. In Arizona Highways,; Book Form, March 1958 April 1958. (Box 101, Folder 10)
      - Stagecoach Press, Bibliography (Introduction to) published by Price Daniels, Bookseller., September 1964. (Box 101, Folder 11)
      - Stelter, B.F., tribute to. Occidental Alumnus, 1946. (Box 101, Folder 12)
      - Stop Thief. ALA History Round Table,; Los Angeles Times,; Wilson Library Bulletin, June 22, 1953 June 1955 December 1953. (Box 101, Folder 13)
      - Street of the Secondhand Bookshops. In Los Angeles Times, June 1955. (Box 101, Folder 14)